and we will begin reading
from verse one.
Matthew chapter 13
verse one when you're there please say
amen.
Amen.
The Bible says, "Then the same day or
the same day went Jesus out of the house
and sat by the seaside,
and great multitudes were gathered
together unto him, so that he went into
a ship, and sat, and the whole multitude
stood on the shore.
And he spake many things unto them in
parables, saying, Behold, a swer went
forth to sow.
And when he sowed, some seeds fell by
the wayside, and the fowls came and
devoured them up. And some fell upon
stony places where they had not much
earth, and forth with they sprung up,
because they had no deepness of earth.
And when the sun was up, they were
scorched, and because they had no root,
they withered away.
And some fell among thorns, and the
thorns sprung up and choked them, but
others fell into good ground and brought
forth fruit, some h 100fold, some
60fold,
some 30fold. Who has ears to hear? Let
him hear.
Then we had the scripture reading where
the disciples asked
Jesus, why do you speak in parables? And
he answered, "Because it is given unto
you to know the mysteries of the
kingdom, but unto them it is not given."
It says, "Because they were slow of
understanding."
And that's why he spoke in parables.
But then in verse 18, Jesus goes on to
explain the meaning of this parable. And
it says here, "Hear ye therefore the
parable of the swer. When anyone heareth
the word of the kingdom, and understands
it not, then cometh the wicked one, and
catcheth away that which was sown in his
heart.
This is he that receives seed
by the wayside.
Jesus here describes this first
part of the parable as those that
receive seed by the wayside. And the
Bible says that those who receive seed
by the wayside are those who do not what
do not what everyone
understand.
They do not understand. What does it
mean to understand?
Help me out. What does it mean to
understand?
That's right. So to understand is to
mentally
comprehend.
And so what God is saying here, the
parable is saying is that those who
represent this first ground, those who
receive seed by the wayside wayside are
those who do not mentally
comprehend.
And the Bible says, "And the wicked one
comes and catcheth away the seed."
So the question is, why does the wicked
one do this? And I want to suggest
something to you this morning that the
wicked one is actually the original
wayside hearer.
You see in this parable Jesus says this
is a parable of the mysteries of the
kingdom of heaven. So I want to look
this morning at this parable in the
context of what actually happened in
heaven.
According to Ezekiel 28:15, the Bible
speaks of Lucifer and says this of him,
"Thou was perfect in thy ways from the
day that thou was created." So what do
you think perfect means?
What is perfect?
Without blemish. What else?
Without fault. Okay. How was he without
blemish or without fault?
How? Physically.
Yes.
Okay. Yes. Is that all?
What else?
Spiritually and mentally.
So, so Lucifer was created physically
whole.
Ment uh spiritually whole and mentally
The word here for perfect, the Hebrew
word tom, it means this entire
integrity, truth, without blemish,
complete, full, perfect, sincerely,
sound.
Sound.
What does that word sound mean to you?
Solid, right?
Stable. So, so let's let's build on
that. Lucifer when he was created he was
mentally sound.
He was mentally stable.
He was mentally holy.
Yes.
Now does anyone know that the word holy
is actually connected also with the word
whole?
Right? To be whole means to be holy. Now
when we think of when like when Jesus
says in his parables or when the Bible
says that someone was made whole, what
do we think of?
You know the man with the leper, he was
what? Healed. He became healthy. He
became healthy. So please follow me now.
When Lucifer was created, he was
mentally whole.
He was mentally healthy.
Satan Lucifer had good mental health.
Yes.
Okay.
So, we understand so far that he was
mentally sound. He was mentally whole.
He was mentally healthy. But then he
began to do something. Did he not?
Let me ask you something. Did he begin
to doubt the word of God?
And let me ask you something. What
happened when he began to doubt the word
of God? What began to happen to him
mentally?
Did he begin to have mental
health
issues?
Yeah.
So, we can say that Lucifer was actually
the first being ever to begin to
experience mental health issues.
Now, don't don't jump ahead of me and
please don't think that I'm saying if
someone has mental health issues, you
know, that that they are somehow of
Lucifer. That's not what I'm saying. But
I need you to follow along carefully.
What did Lucifer begin to do with the
word of God?
He began to doubt it. How many of you
agree with that? Why did he doubt it,
though?
Is it safe to say that there were some
things about the mystery of God that
Lucifer himself did not under
stand? Yes.
And and is it fair to say then that
because of this lack of understanding
that Lucifer
became a wayside hearer?
Yes.
Yeah. Remember in the parable, those who
hear the word of God but do not
understand it, do not comprehend it are
those that are described as wayside
hearers.
So the Bible tells us uh uh that Lucifer
uh created perfect, created mentally
whole begins to doubt and this doubting
leads to mental instability.
He's now got mental health issues. I
want to read a statement to you from
Darkness Before Dawn, page nine. And it
says this. It is a masterpiece of
Satan's deception to keep the minds of
men searching and conjuring in regard to
that which God has not made known and
which he does not intend that we shall
understand. So, are there some things
that God doesn't intend for us to
understand? And we're supposed to be
fine with that. Amen. Yes.
However, it goes on to say here, it was
it was thus that Lucifer lost his place
in heaven. He became dissatisfied
because all the secrets of God's
purposes were not confided to him, and
he entirely disregarded that which was
revealed concerning his own work in his
lofty position assigned him. By arousing
the same discontent in the angels under
his command, he caused their fall. Was
Satan the first wayside hearer?
Yes.
Yeah.
Matthew 13:20.
Jesus goes on to say, "But he that
receive the seed into stony places, the
same is he that heareth the word
and a non with joy receives it. Yet he
has no root in himself, but endureth for
a while. For when tribulation or
persecution arises because of the word
by and by, he is what?
He's offended.
Got another question for you.
Was Lucifer first a happy worshipper of
God?
Yeah. What does it mean to have no root?
So when John the Baptist said, "Now is
the axe laid to the root of the tree."
What was he saying? What is the root of
the tree?
It's the foundation.
It's the foundation of the tree. So let
me ask a question. Is is Christ is the
word of God our solid foundation?
But what happens when you start to doubt
the word of God? Listen carefully. What
happened in Lucifer's mind as he started
to doubt the word of God? Did that
eventually lead him to stony places?
Yes.
I want you to check this out, guys,
because what we're about to see is that
all three of these grounds have their
origination in the mind of Lucifer.
He first doubted the word and now that
led him to this stony place where where
because he has no root
when tribulation or persecution arises
because of the word by and by he is
what?
Offended.
When the word of God called Lucifer to
repent, was he offended?
When the word of God tried to bring
Lucifer back from his place, let me ask
something. Have you ever been offended
when someone pointed out something?
Something not so good about your
character.
It happens, doesn't it? It's kind of
easy to be offended
when someone talks about you.
when someone points something out about
you. And so here Lucifer is because he
no longer has any root, any foundation,
he got rid of that when he started
doubting the word of God.
So because he has no root, no
foundation, he becomes a stony ground
hearer. Now watch this. Uh uh the Bible
tells us
that he also verse 22 he also that
receives seed among the thorns is he
that heareth the word and the care of
this world and the deceitfulness of
riches choke the word and he becomes
unfruitful.
Tell me a little bit about the
deceitfulness of riches.
The deceitfulness of riches kind of like
you know wanting the best for yourself.
kind of like wanting self- glorification
like all about me. So let me ask you a
question. Did Lucifer doubting the word
of God wayside hearer lead him to become
a stony ground hearer offended
by the word of God? Did that ultimately
lead the word of God to be choked out in
his heart because now all he cared about
was self
glorification.
And so what happens? The word of God was
what?
choked out and he becomes unfruitful.
If we could use Lucifer as the first
case study
of what it means to be mentally
unhealthy,
let me break this down, guys. You see,
when we talk about mental health today,
most of us go say, "What?
Yeah, I know somebody with mental health
issues.
Right? And that somebody that we know is
typically not us.
But beloved, according to what we are
reading here, Lucifer is the first
individual to become mentally unstable.
And that mental instability came as a
result of him rejecting the word of God
in his life. Yes.
Now, now please I want you to keep
following on because we know that
onethird of the angels eventually fell
with Lucifer. Is that right? So my
question is how did onethird of the
angels fall?
How did they end up doing what Lucifer
did?
Let me say it this way. They allowed
Lucifer to get into their heads.
Did you catch what I just said?
Yes.
They allowed Lucifer to get into their
head. And when the enemy of souls gets
into your head,
have you ever heard someone say, "Don't
let it get into your head.
Don't let them get into your head.
Lucifer was able to get into the heads
of angels and and for each angel that
fell, one of each of them basically fell
because they became one of these
grounds.
Discontent.
I don't understand why God doesn't let
us in on his plans.
Stony ground. Offended because of the
word of God.
Waste, I'm sorry, thorny ground. uh uh
the the the cares and the the desires of
self- glorification choke out the word.
So the angels that fell in heaven are
all represented by one of these grounds.
But wait a minute,
does the parable go on go on to say that
there was good ground?
Were there angels in heaven that did not
rebel?
Were there angels in heaven that chose
to be obedient to the will and the word
of God? Absolutely.
So, beloved, we've just gone through
this parable and seen its connection to
what happened in heaven. These three
grounds originated in the mind of
Lucifer. It led him to become mentally
unstable,
mentally unhealthy
because of his rejection of the word of
God. and he gets into the heads of other
angels and leads them to the same
results.
The Bible says in Revelation 12:7,
"There was war in heaven. Michael and
his angels fought against the dragon,
and the dragon fought and his angels and
prevailed not, neither was their place
found anymore in heaven. And the great
dragon was cast out, that old serpent
called the devil and Satan, which
deceiveth the whole world. He was cast
out into the earth and his angels were
cast out with him.
So where was Lucifer and his angels
cast?
Out of this earth.
So let's get into scene two.
God creates Adam and Eve. Amen. He makes
them in his what? Image and in his
likeness. Amen. That means he made them
holy.
Amen. What does it mean to be holy?
whole. How were they made whole? How
were they made perfect?
They were physically whole. They were
spiritually whole. And they were what?
Mentally
healthy.
Are you with me?
What happens?
Well,
Genesis chapter 3:4, the the serpent
said unto the woman, "You shall not
surely die.
For God does know that in the day that
you eat thereof, then your eyes shall be
open, and ye shall be as God's, knowing
good and evil."
Let me ask you a question. What does the
word know mean?
What does it mean to know something?
To what?
To understand. So let me ask you a
question now. Was Satan coming to Adam
and Eve in the garden and saying there
are things you don't understand that God
is holding back from you? Did they did
he approach Adam and Eve like that?
What does the parable say?
Those
upon whom the seed is thrown and they
understand what not. Did Satan lead Adam
and Eve to think there are things you
don't understand about God? And as a
result of that, did he plant doubt in
the heart of Eve?
Yes.
Yay. Has God really said that you can't
touch the tree? That you can't eat the
tree.
In the moment that Eve entertains that
doubt, what has she become?
A wayside hearer.
Before she was mentally healthy and
holy, but now she is entertaining doubt.
And what happens to her mentally?
She becomes mentally unstable. Now, I
get what most of us think in here. When
we hear the word mentally unstable, we
think we have our picture of what
mentally unstable means. And I get that
and I'm not discounting that. But what
I'm trying to tell you is that in
heaven's eyes,
there is another meaning for mentally
unstable.
And it is when you get off of the shore
foundation of the word of God, you
become mentally unstable. Even though
you can hold a job and even though you
can go about life's activities as if
nothing is wrong, heaven says that is
mentally unhealth unhealthy.
So So Lucifer leads Adam and Eve to or
Eve specifically to doubt the word of
God.
Remember the parable. But he that
receives seed into the stony places, the
same is he that hears the word and an on
with joy receives it, yet has no root in
himself, but endureth for a while. For
when tribulation or persecution arises
because of the word, by and by he is
offended. So my question is, having
removed the root, the foundation, which
is trust in the word of God, did Adam or
did Eve now become offended at the word
of God?
Huh? God is hiding something from me.
How dare he?
And now listen, with that doubt firmly
planted, with the root gone, the
foundation gone, and she is now
entertaining doubt, and she is now
offended at the word of God, my question
is, do the cares of this world overtake
her love for God?
Yes.
Because now she's realizing, hey, I can
be much more than God. I can have
freedom outside of God. I can do my own
thing. And the cares of this world
choked out
the word.
In other words, beloved, the same thing
that happened with Lucifer in heaven in
heaven now is happening to Adam and Eve
in the garden.
And the Bible says here in verse 6, uh
uh when the woman saw that the tree was
good for food, and that it was pleasant
to the eyes, and a tree desired to make
one wise, she took of the fruit thereof
and did eat, and gave also unto her
husband with her, and he did eat, and
the eyes of them both were open, and
they knew that they were naked, and they
sewed fig leaves together, and made
themselves aprons. So, let me ask a
question. Were Adam and Eve's eyes
closed before they ate of the tree?
Were they closed? No. How do we know
they weren't closed?
Because she seized the serpent.
The Bible says when when they saw that
when she saw that the tree was good for
for for food. In other words,
the eyes that are being opened are not
her literal eyes. Anyone ever say, "I
see what you're talking about."
What does that mean?
I understand. Her understanding was or
her mind was open. But the question is
what mind was opened? The answer is it
was the carnal mind.
And beloved, the carnal mind is a
mentally unhealthy and unstable
mind.
And so their minds are open. And and now
check this out. When their minds are
open, what have they lost? mentality
stability, mental health.
Now watch this. God comes to them in the
garden, right? And you remember what God
said to Adam? First of all, what do they
do when God comes to them in a garden?
Why are they hiding?
Because they're what?
Yeah. Give me something else, though. I
know they're afraid but give you because
they are
mentally
unstable, mentally unhealthy. They are
now looking at God as one who is coming
to destroy them. They're looking at God
with fear. They are discouraged. They
are depressed. Are they feeling all
these things?
And then watch this. God says to them,
"Who told you that you were naked?
You've read that verse before, right?
Who told you?
Who? Somebody told Adam and Eve that
they were naked?
Who do you think it was that told them
that?
Along with
Satan. You know what Satan does? Satan
leads you to move away from the word of
God. He leads you to doubt the word of
God and then he points to your shame.
That's what he does.
And basically what he is doing is he's
he is getting into your
head.
That's what he's all about.
If I can get into your head and tell you
how how how how wicked you are, how how
how you know far away from God you are,
if I can get into your head and totally
discourage you and totally move you away
from the foundation which is the word of
God, then I have you in the palm of my
hand.
That's what he's trying to do.
I would suggest to you, don't let Satan
get into your head
because that's what he does does,
beloved. He gets into your head to try
to drive you into mental instability.
What were the signs of their mental
instability?
Depression.
discouragement,
fear,
and I ask you when when you look at
these the the the fruit of their
rejection of the word of God, you can
see how as a society, you wonder why,
you know, mental health cases are, you
know, growing and mental health has
become such a big issue. Beloved, I
believe that part of the reason is
because as mankind continues on, we get
further and further away from God.
So, Adam and Eve,
all three grounds are manifested in
them.
And this is why Genesis 3:15, the Bible
says God comes to them in a garden and
says, "I will put enmity between thee
and the woman and between."
Between what?
Thy seed and who?
What is the parable talking about?
A swer
went forth to what?
Sow.
Beloved, listen to me. In this text, God
is as it were saying, listen, the
purpose of the gospel
is to redeem you from the stony ground.
It is to redeem you from the wayside
ground. It is to redeem you from the
thorny ground. In other words, listen
beloved, we come into this world
mentally
unstable
because the carnal mind is what? Enmity
against God.
This verse tells us that God was going
to send seed that would result
in bringing us back into our right
minds.
God cares about your depression.
Amen.
He cares about your fears. He cares
about your discouragements and the
purpose of the gospel is to deliver you
from those things.
So God begins sewing the word.
You see this parable also explains the
history of the entire Old Testament.
You'll remember that the first ground
represented those who did not
understand. Are are you with me? Well,
listen. After the fall of man, you can
read through the book of Genesis all the
way up to Genesis chapter 6 where as man
began to multiply. They became evil. And
the Bible says in Genesis 6 that their
hearts, God saw that the hearts of men
were only what?
Evil continually.
The imaginations of men and that word
imagination points to the understanding.
So if the understanding of men was only
evil continually, it represents a group
of people who are wayside hearers.
And because they did not understand the
word of God, what ends up happening to
them? A flood comes and they are
destroyed.
Well, after the flood, we have the story
of Abraham. And Abraham comes upon the
scene. He's going to be the father of a
very great what? a very great nation, a
very great multitude. But you know what
happened to this nation, right? This
nation Israel, uh they end up uh in
captivity to Egypt for 400 years. And
then God comes to deliver them. But
check this out. Through that process,
the children of Israel are experiencing
persecution and tribulation, are they
not? And yet because they had no root
in, many of them had no root in
themselves. Did they make it into the
promised land?
The first ground, think with me. The
first ground,
the flood, wayside hearers. We don't
understand the word and therefore we
reject it. The second ground, stony
ground hearers going through persecution
and we're going to murmur and complain
and we're offended when God comes to try
to correct us. That is the whole history
of Old Testament Israel,
particularly their journey from Egypt
into the promised land. But there is a
third ground. You remember this ground
represents those who the cares of the
world choke out the word. Let me ask you
a question. When the children of Israel
get into the promised land,
we've got it good. Now, we're settled in
the promised land. Did the cares of
worldliness begin to enter into Israel?
Yes.
And you know the story
because they actually continued on like
that until they enter ended up in
Babylonian captivity and then God set
them free again. And now check this out.
We think that whoa what is going to
happen to the people of God because it
just seems like they continue to mess
up. But beloved, there is a fourth
ground and that fourth ground is the
ground in which good fruit would be
brought forth.
You say pastor what is that fourth
ground? Jesus himself when he comes to
this earth he tells us in the book of
John 12:23 he says in fact before we
even read that Jesus Christ is the very
seed that Genesis 3:15 was talking about
and what did he say about himself in
John 12:23 Jesus answered them saying
the hour is come that the son of man
should be glorified verily I say unto
you. Except a corn of wheat fall into
the ground and die, it abideth alone.
But if it die, it brings forth much
fruit. Praise God for the coming of
Jesus
because every ground before him yielded
very little good.
But when he came upon the scene, he was
that seed that was planted into good
ground. and from his death, burial, and
resurrection, he would bring forth much
fruit.
So watch this.
When Satan comes, when Jesus comes on
the scene, Satan knows that this is the
seed. Did you hear me? Satan knows that
this is a seed. So what does he do? He
approaches him in the wilderness.
How many times does he tempt the seed?
Three times. You think those three times
have anything to do with the three
grounds?
Wait, wait, wait. You got to see this
because in Matthew chapter 3, Matthew,
Matthew chapter 4, verse 2, it says,
"When he had fasted 40 days and 40
nights, he was afterward hungered, and
when the tempter came to him, he said,
if thou be the son of God, command that
these stones be made bread. But he
answered and said, It is written, man
shall not live by bread alone, but by
every what?
Word that proceeds out of the mouth of
God.
Beloved, listen to me. Satan was trying
to get into the head
of Jesus.
Doubt the word of God.
Jesus, do you really understand why
you're here? Do you really understand
your mission? Like, like, why don't you
just go ahead and eat? But Jesus said,
"No, I will eat when my father tells me
to eat."
It's as if Jesus was Satan was saying to
him, "Yay, has God said that you shall
not eat."
And Jesus rebukes him by saying, "Man
shall not live by bread alone, but by
every what? Word that proceeds out of
the mouth of God." In other words, he's
saying, "My foundation is sure,
and as long as I stand upon the word of
God, you cannot get into my
head."
The second temptation, he takes him to a
high place and says, "Throw yourself
down." Right there, he's tempting them,
tempting him, saying, "Look, you know,
he's trying to offend him. Are you
really the son of God? If you're really
the son of God, prove it. Throw yourself
down. He's trying. You know, if someone
said came to you and said, "Are you
really a Christian?" How many of you
would probably get offended?
And maybe you might not cuz you're like,
"Yeah." But how many of you would be
like, "You know what? How dare you ask
me
if I'm a follower of Jesus?"
And the person said, "Oh, yeah. Well,
prove it." How many of you How many of
you would go out and prove it?
He was trying to get Jesus to be
offended, but Jesus said, "I'm not even
going there because I trust my father."
When the word of God is on is when
you're solidly standing on the word of
God, Satan cannot get into your head.
The Bible says, "Great peace have they
which love thy law, and what? Nothing
shall offend them.
And then you know the third thing Satan
does, right?
He shows Jesus all the glories and the
riches of the world.
What was the thorny ground about?
The cares and the riches of the He's
trying to choke the word out of Jesus.
And Jesus overcomes all because he is
mentally sound.
He overcomes all these grounds and goes
on to produce much fruit in his
ministry, doesn't he?
Doesn't he?
He is the seed that was planted in the
good ground. And so you I want you to
understand beloved how how deep this
parable is because it's trying to show
us something that when Christ overcame
he was basically he was basically
showing saying listen I want you to
understand the mind that is in me.
Let this mind
that is in me
be also in you.
Why? Cuz without this mind, Satan's
going to get into your head
and he's going to lead you to doubt me
and to not trust and to fear and to be
discouraged and to be down. He's going
to lead you to do all these things. So
I'm trying to show you, look, he tried
to get into my head and he could not.
Why? Because of this mind.
I want that mind to be
in you,
beloved. That's the purpose of the
gospel.
He's trying to remove our minds and get
us into his mind.
So, watch this.
Jesus comes and that's the goal. That's
the the the gift he's offering. A new
mind, a new heart will I give you. But
you know what? It's it's amazing
because there was a prophecy, right,
that stated that Jesus would was coming
and and I know we talking about Genesis
3:15, but there was another prophecy in
the book of Daniel and it was called the
70we prophecy. That 70we prophecy
pointed to the coming of Christ, but I
want you to follow this carefully, my
beloved. Listen carefully.
Did the Jews
understand
the mission of Christ
and so they rejected him.
Oh, so we might say that the Jews were
wayside hearers.
I'm I'm giving you the seed. That's the
son of God. But the Jews, they were
like, "Yeah, no, we don't understand."
And so they rejected him.
Okay. What about the disciples?
Did persecution come upon the disciples
that led them to forsake Jesus?
Yes.
Didn't Jesus say, "Smite the shepherd
and the sheep will be what?
Will be scattered."
Why did they flee Jesus?
Well,
they understood his mission,
but why did they flee?
Literally speaking, why did they run?
Why did they run away? Why did they Why
were they Do you remember when they were
hiding in the in the uh they were hiding
for fear?
They were hiding for persecution.
Remember Jesus said, "You all should
leave me this night." And and then and
then uh uh Peter said, "What?" And Peter
got offended.
Peter got what's the word I just used?
Offended. Lord, though everyone forsake
you, I will never forsake you. Did he
forsake Jesus
in time of persecution? And so, so even
the disciples,
even the disciples represented one of
those grounds.
Now, the Romans are the ones that put
him to death.
All they cared about was what?
The cares of this world.
In other words, all everyone surrounding
Jesus represented one of those grounds
in his death.
No one stood with him. He was the seed
that was planted in good ground. But
check this out, beloved. Praise God.
Because when Jesus dies and is buried
and resurrected, listen to what happens.
A Roman soldier,
the centurion looks upon his dead body
and says, "Truly, this was the son of
God." On the day of Pentecost, Jews,
remember the same ones that were, check
this out, guys, they rejected him all
because they were all mentally
unstable. But he dies
in order to save people from all those
categories.
Yes,
he saved the Romans. Jews, devout Jews
from all over the world were were in
Jerusalem on the day of Pentecost. They
were converted. And of course, we know
the disciples who at one time forsook
him
were now his chief
promoters.
Beloved, Jesus died
to save all of us from our mental health
issues because guess what? We have them.
We
have them.
Don't look down at your nose at someone
who you think, "Oh, yeah, that person
has mental issues because they are
suffering with discouragement or guess
what? All have sinned and fall short of
the glory of God. All struggle with the
carnal mind. And the carnal mind is
designed to keep you mentally unstable
in the eyes of heaven.
God tells us
that he sent his son into the world to
save us from our sins, to save us from
our discouragement, to save us from the
things that make us mentally unstable in
the eyes of heaven.
So watch this, guys. If if the Jews
represented
that group of people when the seed was
planted, they were wayside hearers.
That's the 70we prophecy. Is there
another time prophecy after the 70
weeks?
The answer is yes. Otherwise, I would
not have asked.
Is there a time prophecy after the 70
weeks in the book of Daniel?
Yes, it is the 1260year
time prophecy. What happens in that time
prophecy?
What per person? What? Persecution.
Watch this guys. In the 70we prophecy,
the Jews represent the first ground.
They did not understand and therefore
they rejected the word of God. But in
the next prophecy, the 1260, that
represents a group of people who go
through persecution. And if you're not
grounded on the word of God, you fall
away. They fell away during that
persecution.
I'm going somewhere with this.
So if the first ground can be tied to
the 70 weeks and the second ground can
be tied to the 1260, then the third
ground, the Is there a third prophecy?
What is that prophecy?
The 2300 day time prophecy. And what is
the issue with the third ground,
the cares of this world?
It's no longer persecution because we're
not living through persecution today,
are we? It's no longer not understanding
who the Messiah is. We all know who he
is. But beloved, listen to me. The thing
we are dealing with most today is the
cares of this world. Did Jesus say just
before he comes again that it'll be like
in the days of Noah? They'll be marrying
and giving in marriage and people will
not know until
he comes again.
Yes,
beloved. Being caught up in the cares of
this world and not understanding that
the foundation of your walk is the word
of God, it leads to mental health
issues.
And let me speak very clearly. You see,
when you have anger issues, that's a
mental health problem.
Y'all not feeling me?
When you don't love your neighbor, that
is a mental health issue.
When you have hatred in your heart, that
When you cannot get along, when you
argue, when you do all these things,
when you are not walking in the
character and likeness of Christ, you
are dealing with a mental health issue.
Listen
carefully guys
because though the first ground the 7we
prophecy are those that are wayside
hearers and though the second ground the
1260 are those who go through
persecution and either stay firm or fell
out of the truth because of persecution.
And though that last the the the third
ground represents th the the hearers who
are taken up with the cares of this
world. There is a fourth ground and it
is the ground called the good ground.
At the end of time, God is going to have
a people who are bringing forth much
fruit to the glory of God.
And what is that fruit? It is the fruit
of the spirit which is love, joy, peace,
longsuffering, gentleness, goodness,
faith, meekness, temperance which
demonstrates that you are mentally
holy,
healthy,
stable.
Thus the Bible says, "Grieve not the
spirit of God whereby you are sealed."
Who is God going to be sealing at the
end of time? Those who are mentally
stable. What does that mean, pastor?
Those who know how to love.
Those who know how to be forgiving.
Those who know how to be merciful.
Because beloved, listen to me. If you
don't have that, let me tell it to you
again. You are suffering with mental
instability. And yes, God's church,
there are people in God's church, many
people who suffer with mental
instability.
And it's not because, oh, they're crazy.
No, it's just because they don't have
love in their hearts.
Beloved, don't let Satan get in your
head.
Because if he gets in your head, he's
going to make you mentally unstable.
He's going to lead you to not like
people for literally no reason. I don't
like him. Why? Ah,
I'm not sure. Man, you're crazy.
That's mental instability.
When you are at war with someone for
reasons you don't even know, that's
mental instability.
And Satan will bring that men mental
instability right here into the house of
God, into the church of God. And he will
do it on Sabbath morning.
And he will do it to try to get into
your head.
When Jesus comes again,
there's going to be a group of people
who rise up from the ground.
It's not going to be the wayside hearers
because they were never planted.
It's not going to be the stony ground
hearers because they could not bring
forth fruit. It's not going to be the
thorny ground hearers because they were
not ready for God. It's only going to be
those who died in Christ.
So the Bible says that the Lord himself
shall descend from heaven with a shout,
with the voice of the archangel, and the
dead.
The dead where?
In Christ.
Now beloved, we can just stop right
there and I want you to understand the
dead in Christ represent two groups of
people. The dead and the living.
Did you catch that?
Because you can be dead and dead in
Christ, but you can also be alive and
dead in Christ.
So beloved, it is only the dead in
Christ, those who died in Christ and
were buried with him
that will be caught up because they
represent the first fruits, the good
fruits that will be brought forth when
Jesus comes again. Amen.
Beloved, there are many people who are
struggling with mental health issues.
And for far too long, we put off mental
health as something that those people
struggle with. Yay, they have mental
health issues. And we need to pray for
them. But beloved, I'm here to tell you
today that if you carry animosity in
your heart against a fellow brother or
sister, if you cannot speak peaceibly
unto a fellow brother or sister, if you
cannot speak peacefully in your home or
wherever it is you have mental health
issues and the only way they can be
solved is to let the mind of Christ,
be in you,
beloved. That's why he gives us that
helmet of salvation so that Satan cannot
get into
your heads.
I'm closing with this.
There's a parable of a demoniac.
You guys remember this story? The
demoniac was cutting himself.
You know, isn't cutting one of those
signs of depression?
And here you have this demoniac cutting
himself and he's he is in the tombs and
chains couldn't hold him. Nothing could
be done for him. And then the Bible
tells us that that Jesus comes to the
shore and when the demoniac sees him, he
runs to Jesus and says, "What have we to
do with thee?" And Jesus says, "What is
your name?" And he says, "My name is
what?" "Leion, for we are many." Let me
ask you, do you think that legion
represented all those grounds?
[Music]
The ground of the wayside her. ground of
the stony ground heroer, the ground of
the thorny ground. All of those were in
this man.
And the Bible tells us that Jesus had
power to rebuke these demons.
[Music]
And I love I love how the verse puts it.
I I got to read it to you. Uh it's just
one verse. It's Matthew I'm sorry.
Mark chapter 5. I will read it in your
hearing.
After the demons are cast out and and
they run into these pigs and the pigs
run down this hill, the Bible says that
the people uh verse 14, they that had
fed the swine told in the city and in
the country and they went out to see
what it was that was done. And they come
to Jesus and see him that was possessed
with the devil and had the legions the
legions sitting and clothed
and in
his
right
mind.
[Music]
But other God wants us to be in our
right minds.
It's the mind that he designed for us
which is the mind of Christ.
But many of us get offended by that
mind. Many of us don't understand that
mind. Many of us, the cares of this
world are more important than that mind.
And as a result, we never get the mind
of Christ.
And as a result of not having the mind
of Christ, Satan has free access to get
into your head all day long and all
night long.
It's time to get Satan out of your head.
It's time for us to get the mind of
Christ. It's time for us to put on the
helmet of salvation. Beloved,
[Music]
my appeal to you this morning,
give me the mind of Christ.
Give me the mind of Christ. Why? Because
I am suffering with mental
health issues.
And Lord, I need your mind to counteract
the lies, the discouragement, the
depression, the fear, the worry that
Satan has me playing over and over and
over again in my mind. If that's you,
I'm going to ask you to stand to your
feet. It may not be all of you, but
you're saying today, "Yeah, I've got
mental health issues, and I freely
acknowledge that. Lord, please
deliver me from this anger. Deliver me
from this hatred. Deliver me from this
depression and this discouragement.
I don't want Satan getting in my head
any longer.
Heavenly Father,
[Music]
forgive us for we have sinned.
Forgive us, Lord, for allowing the enemy
to get into our heads.
[Music]
He has told us
that we are no good, that we are
unworthy,
[Music]
that there is no hope.
But Lord, we choose not to believe his
lies.
Let the mind that was in your son Jesus,
we ask that mind to be in us now.
Heal us Lord
that we may have the fruit
of the spirit.
We thank you Jesus for hearing and
answering because we ask it
in the precious name of Jesus. Amen.
And amen. Would you remain standing as
we sing our closing song?
Our
closing song is Give Me Jesus in number
305. Give me Jesus.